<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.kde.step.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>Step</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Step</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Stap</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">Step</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Step</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Step</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxStepxx</name>
  <summary>Interactive Physical Simulator</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Simulador interactiu de física</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Interactieve natuurkundige simulaties</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Simulador de Física Interativo</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Interaktiv fysiksimulator</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Інтерактивний фізичний імітатор</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxInteractive Physical Simulatorxx</summary>
  <description>
    <p>Step is an interactive physical simulator. It allows you to explore the physical world through simulations. It works like this: you place some bodies on the scene, add some forces such as gravity or springs, then click Simulate and Step shows you how your scene will evolve according to the laws of physics. You can change every property of the bodies/forces in your experiment (even during simulation) and see how this will change evolution of the experiment. With Step you cannot only learn but feel how physics works!</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Step és un simulador interactiu de física. Us permet explorar el món físic a través de simulacions. Funciona així: col·loqueu alguns cossos a l'escena, afegiu algunes forces com ara molles o la gravetat, cliqueu Simula i l'Step us mostra com evolucionarà l'escena segons les lleis de la física. Podeu canviar cadascuna de les propietats dels cossos o forces del vostre experiment (fins i tot durant la simulació) i veure com això afectarà l'evolució de l'experiment. Amb l'Step no només podeu aprendre sinó també podeu sentir com funciona la física!</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Step é um simulador de física interativo. Permite-lhe explorar o mundo da física através de simulações. Funciona da seguinte forma: Você coloca alguns corpos no cenário, adiciona algumas forças como a gravidade ou molas e então clica em Simular, para que o Step lhe mostre como o seu cenário irá evoluir de acordo com as leis da física. Você poderá alterar qualquer propriedade dos corpos/forças da sua experiência (inclusive durante a simulação) para ver como isso irá mudar a evolução da experiência. Com o Step você poderá não só aprender, mas também sentir como funciona a física!</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Step är en interaktiv fysiksimulator. Den låter dig utforska den fysiska värden genom simuleringar. Den fungerar så här: Du placerar några kroppar i diagrammet, lägger till några krafter som gravitation eller fjädrar, och klickar därefter på Simulera så visar Step dig hur diagrammet förändras enligt fysikens lagar. Du kan ändra alla egenskaper hos kropparna och krafterna i experimentet (till och med under simuleringen) och se hur det påverkar experimentets förlopp. Med Step kan du inte bara lära dig hur fysiken fungerar, utan också få en känsla för det.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Step є інтерактивним імітатором фізичних процесів. Він надає вам змогу вивчати фізичні явища за допомогою їх імітації. Ось як він працює: ви розташовуєте у дослідній області деякі тіла, додаєте сили їх взаємодії (такі як гравітаційні сили та пружні сили у вигляді пружин), а потім натискаєте кнопку «Імітувати, — Step покаже як розвиватимуться події у побудованій вами системі з плином часу відповідно до законів фізики. Ви можете змінювати всі властивості тіл або сил у вашому експерименті (навіть під час імітації), щоб побачити як такі зміни впливають на перебіг експерименту. За допомогою Step ви не просто вивчите фізику, а відчуєте як працюють фізичні закони!</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxStep is an interactive physical simulator. It allows you to explore the physical world through simulations. It works like this: you place some bodies on the scene, add some forces such as gravity or springs, then click Simulate and Step shows you how your scene will evolve according to the laws of physics. You can change every property of the bodies/forces in your experiment (even during simulation) and see how this will change evolution of the experiment. With Step you cannot only learn but feel how physics works!xx</p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Característiques:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Kenmerken:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Funcionalidades:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Funktioner:</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Можливості:</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxFeatures:xx</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Classical mechanical simulation in two dimensions</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Simulador de mecànica clàssica en dues dimensions</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Simulatie in twee dimensies volgens de klassieke mechanica</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Simulação mecânica clássica em duas dimensões</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Simulering av klassisk mekanik i två dimensioner</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Імітація класичної механічної взаємодії у двох вимірах</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxClassical mechanical simulation in two dimensionsxx</li>
      <li>Particles, springs with damping, gravitational and coulomb forces</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Partícules, molles amb amortiment, forces gravitacionals i de Coulomb</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Deeltjes, veren met demping, zwaarte- en elektrische krachten</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Partículas, molas com forças potenciais, gravitacionais e de Coulomb</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Partiklar, dämpade fjädrar, gravitationskrafter och coulombkrafter</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Частинки, пружини з елементами в’язкості, гравітаційні і кулонові сили</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxParticles, springs with damping, gravitational and coulomb forcesxx</li>
      <li>Rigid bodies</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Cossos rígids</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Stijve lichamen</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corpos rígidos</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Stela kroppar</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Тверді тіла</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxRigid bodiesxx</li>
      <li>Collision detection (currently only discrete) and handling</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Detecció de col·lisions (ara per ara només discretes) i el seu maneig</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Botsingdetectie (nu nog alleen discreet) en afhandeling</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Detecção e tratamento de colisões (atualmente somente discretas)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Detektering och hantering av kollisioner (för närvarande bara diskreta)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Виявлення (у цій версії лише дискретне) і керування зіткненнями</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxCollision detection (currently only discrete) and handlingxx</li>
      <li>Soft (deformable) bodies simulated as user-editable particles-springs system, sound waves</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Cossos tous (deformables) simulats com a sistemes partícula-molla editables per l'usuari, ones de so</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Zachte (vervormbare) lichamen gesimuleerd als een deeltjes-veersysteem dat door de gebruiker kan worden bewerkt, geluidsgolven</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corpos suaves (deformáveis) simulados como um sistema de partículas-ondas editáveis pelo usuário, ondas sonoras</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Mjuka (deformerbara) kroppar simulerade som system med partiklar och fjädrar redigerbara av användaren, ljudvågor</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">М’які (пружні) тіла імітуються як система з часточок і пружин, з можливістю зміни її параметрів користувачем, рух якої описують гармонічні функції</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxSoft (deformable) bodies simulated as user-editable particles-springs system, sound wavesxx</li>
      <li>Molecular dynamics (currently using Lennard-Jones potential): gas and liquid, condensation and evaporation, calculation of macroscopic quantities and their variances</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Dinàmica molecular (actualment utilitzant el potencial de Lennard-Jones): gas i líquid, la condensació i l'evaporació, el càlcul de quantitats macroscòpiques i les seves variàncies</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Moleculaire dynamica (thans wordt de Lennard-Jones potentiaal gebruikt): gas en vloeistof, condensatie en verdamping, berekening van macroscopische hoeveelheden en hun varianties</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Dinâmica molecular (usando o potencial de Lennard-Jones atualmente): gases e líquidos, condensação e evaporação, cálculo de quantidades macroscópicas e as suas variâncias</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Molekyldynamik (för närvarande med användning av Lennard-Jones potentialen): gaser och vätskor, kondensering och avdunstning, beräkning av makroskopiska kvantiteter och deras varians</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Молекулярна динаміка (у цій версії з використанням потенціалу Леннарда-Джонса): газ і рідина, конденсація і випаровування, обчислення макроскопічних величин та їх змін</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxMolecular dynamics (currently using Lennard-Jones potential): gas and liquid, condensation and evaporation, calculation of macroscopic quantities and their variancesxx</li>
      <li>Units conversion and expression calculation: you can enter something like "(2 days + 3 hours) * 80 km/h" and it will be accepted as distance value (requires libqalculate)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Conversió d'unitats i càlcul d'expressions: podeu introduir quelcom del tipus "(2 dies + 3 hores) * 80 km/h" i serà acceptat com un valor de distància (necessita la libqalculate)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Conversie van eenheden en berekening van expressies zoals "(2 dagen + 3 uren) * 80 km/h", waarna dit zal worden beschouwd als een afstand (vereist libqalculate)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Conversão de unidades e cálculo de expressões; você poderá indicar algo do tipo "(2 dias + 3 horas) * 80 km/h", e isto será aceito como um valor de distância (necessita da 'libqalculate')</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Enhetskonvertering och uttrycksberäkning: Du kan skriva in någonting i stil med "(2 dagar + 3 timmar) * 80 km/h", vilket accepteras som ett avståndsvärde (kräver libqalculate)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Перетворення одиниць і обчислення виразів: ви можете ввести щось на зразок «(2 дні + 3 години) * 80 км/г» і цю величину буде прийнято як значення відстані (для того, щоб це працювало слід встановити libqalculate)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxUnits conversion and expression calculation: you can enter something like "(2 days + 3 hours) * 80 km/h" and it will be accepted as distance value (requires libqalculate)xx</li>
      <li>Errors calculation and propagation: you can enter values like "1.3 ± 0.2" for any property and errors for all dependent properties will be calculated using statistical formulas</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Càlcul i propagació d'errors: podeu introduir valors del tipus "1.3 ± 0.2" a qualsevol propietat i els errors de totes les propietats que en depenguin es calcularan utilitzant fórmules estadístiques</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Foutenberekening en -voortplanting: u kunt voor elke eigenschap zoiets invullen als "1,3 ± 0,2", waarna voor elke daarvan afhankelijke eigenschap de fouten zullen worden berekend met gebruik van statistische formules</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Cálculo e propagação de erros: você poderá indicar valores do tipo "1.3 ± 0.2" para qualquer propriedade, para que sejam calculados os erros de todas as propriedades dependentes com fórmulas estatísticas</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Felberäkning och felpropagering: Du kan skriva in värden som "1,3 ± 0,2" för alla egenskaper, och fel för alla beroende egenskaper beräknas med statistiska formler</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Обчислення і поширення похибок: ви можете вводити значення на зразок «1.3 ± 0.2» для будь-якої з властивостей, і похибки для всіх властивостей, що залежать від вказаної властивості, буде обчислено за статистичними формулами</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxErrors calculation and propagation: you can enter values like "1.3 ± 0.2" for any property and errors for all dependent properties will be calculated using statistical formulasxx</li>
      <li>Solver error estimation: errors introduced by the solver is calculated and added to user-entered errors</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Estimació dels errors del solucionador: Els errors introduïts pel solucionador es calculen i s'afegeixen als errors introduïts per l'usuari</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Het afschatten van fouten veroorzaakt door de oplossingsmethode: fouten die bij het oplossen zijn ontstaan worden berekend en opgeteld bij de fouten die door de gebruiker zijn ingevoerd</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Estimativa do erro da resolução: os erros introduzidos pela resolução são calculados e adicionados aos erros adicionados pelo usuário</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Feluppskattning av evalueringsenheten: fel som införs av evalueringsenheten beräknas och läggs till användarinmatade fel</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Оцінка похибки розв’язувача: похибки, що виникають внаслідок застосування числових методів розв’язання задач, обчислюються і додаються до введених користувачем похибок</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxSolver error estimation: errors introduced by the solver is calculated and added to user-entered errorsxx</li>
      <li>Several different solvers: up to 8th order, explicit and implicit, with or without adaptive timestep (most of the solvers require GSL library)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Diversos solucionadors diferents: fins a ordre 8è, explícit o implícit, amb pas temporal adaptatiu o sense (la majoria de solucionadors necessiten la biblioteca GSL)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Er zijn diverse oplossingsmethoden: tot aan de 8e orde, expliciet en impliciet, met of zonder een adaptieve tijdstap (voor de meesten is de GSL-bibliotheek nodig)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Diversos métodos de resolução diferentes: até à 8ª ordem, explícitos e implícitos, com ou sem passos temporais adaptativos (a maioria destes métodos necessitam da biblioteca GSL)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Flera olika evalueringsenheter: Upp till 8:e ordningens, explicit eller implicit, med eller utan adaptivt tidssteg (de flesta evalueringsenheter kräver GSL-biblioteket)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Декілька різних розв’язувачів: аж до восьмого порядку, явні і неявні, з та без зміни кроку за часом (більшість з розв’язувачів потребують бібліотеки GSL)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxSeveral different solvers: up to 8th order, explicit and implicit, with or without adaptive timestep (most of the solvers require GSL library)xx</li>
      <li>Controller tool to easily control properties during simulation (even with custom keyboard shortcuts)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Eina controladora per controlar fàcilment les propietats durant la simulació (àdhuc amb dreceres de teclat personalitzades)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Hulpmiddel voor het eenvoudig beheersen van eigenschappen tijdens een simulatie (zelfs met aangepaste sneltoetsen)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Uma ferramenta de controle para modificar facilmente as propriedades durante a simulação (até mesmo com atalhos de teclado personalizados)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Styrverktyg för att enkelt hantera egenskaper under simuleringen (också med egna snabbtangenter)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Інструмент «регулятор» призначено для простого керування властивостями під час імітації (можна навіть призначити власні клавіатурні скорочення для керування регулятором)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxController tool to easily control properties during simulation (even with custom keyboard shortcuts)xx</li>
      <li>Tools to visualize results: graph, meter, tracer</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Eines per visualitzar resultats: gràfics, aparells de mesura, traçadors</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Hulpmiddelen voor het visualiseren van de resultaten: grafiek, meter, spoor</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Ferramentas para visualização dos resultados: gráficos, medidores, impressão</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Verktyg för att åskådliggöra resultat: grafer, mätare, spår</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Інструменти для візуалізації результатів: графік, вимірювач, траєкторія</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxTools to visualize results: graph, meter, tracerxx</li>
      <li>Context information for all objects, integrated wikipedia browser</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Informació contextual per a tots els objectes, integrant la Viquipèdia en el navegador</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Contekstinformatie voor alle objecten, geïntegreerde wikipedia-browser</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Informação de contexto para todos os objetos, navegador do Wikipédia integrado</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Sammanhangsberoende information för alla objekt, inbyggd Wikipedia-bläddrare</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Контекстна інформація щодо всіх об’єктів, інтегрований переглядач вікіпедії</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxContext information for all objects, integrated wikipedia browserxx</li>
      <li>Collection of example experiments, more can be downloaded with KNewStuff</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Col·lecció d'experiments d'exemple. Se'n poden baixar més amb KNewStuff</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Verzameling van voorbeeldexperimenten, meer kunnen er worden opgehaald met KNewStuff</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Coleção de experiências de exemplo, podendo obter mais com o KNewStuff</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">En samling exempel på experiment, och fler kan laddas ner via Hämta heta nyheter</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Збірка зразкових експериментів, додаткові експерименти можна отримати за допомогою KNewStuff</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxCollection of example experiments, more can be downloaded with KNewStuffxx</li>
      <li>Integrated tutorials</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Guies d'aprenentatge integrades</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Geïntegreerd lesmateriaal</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Tutoriais integrados</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Integrerade handledningar</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Вбудовані підручники</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxIntegrated tutorialsxx</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://edu.kde.org/step/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=step</url>
  <url type="help">http://docs.kde.org/stable/en/kdeedu/step/index.html</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>http://kde.org/images/screenshots/step.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>step</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
