<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>step.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>Step</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">Step</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Step</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Step</name>
  <name xml:lang="nds">Step</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Step</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">Krok</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Passo</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">Step</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Step</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Step</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxStepxx</name>
  <summary>Interactive Physical Simulator</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Interaktivní fyzikální simulátor</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Simulador físico interactivo</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Simulateur physique interactif</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nds">Brukerstüert Physiksimuleren</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Interactieve natuurkundige simulaties</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Interaktywny symulator fizyczny</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Simulador de Física Interactivo</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Simulador de Física Interativo</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Interaktívny fyzikálny simulátor</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Інтерактивний фізичний імітатор</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxInteractive Physical Simulatorxx</summary>
  <description>
    <p>Step is an interactive physical simulator. It allows you to explore the physical world through simulations. It works like this: you place some bodies on the scene, add some forces such as gravity or springs, then click Simulate and Step shows you how your scene will evolve according to the laws of physics. You can change every property of the bodies/forces in your experiment (even during simulation) and see how this will change evolution of the experiment. With Step you cannot only learn but feel how physics works!</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Step est un simulateur physique interactif. Il vous permet d'explorer le monde physique au travers de simulations. Il fonctionne comme ceci : vous placez quelques corps sur l'espace de travail, vous ajoutez quelques forces tels que la gravité ou des ressorts, puis vous cliquez sur Simuler et Step vous montre comme votre espace de travail évolue en suivant les lois de la physique. Vous pouvez modifier chaque propriétés des corps/forces dans votre expérience (même durant la simulation) et voir comment cela modifiera l'évolution de l'expérience. Avec Step vous ne ferez pas qu'apprendre mais vous ressentirez comment la physique fonctionne !</p>
    <p xml:lang="nds">Step is en brukerstüert Physik-Simulater. Du kannst dor de physikaalsche Welt mit över Simuleren bekieken. Dat geiht so: Du leggst en poor Körpers hen, föögst en poor Kräft to, so as de Swoorkraft oder en Fedder, denn klickst Du op „Simuleren“ un Step wiest Di, wodennig sik dat na de physikaalschen Gesetten utwickeln deit. Du kannst all Egenschappen vun Dien Körpers un Kräft ännern (ok bides de Simuleren löppt) un Di ankieken wodennig dat den Afloop vun't Experiment ännert. Mit Step kannst Du nich bloots lehren, man meist föhlen, wodennig Physik funkscheneert.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Step is een interactief natuurkundig simulatieprogramma. U kunt ermee natuurkundige experimenten doen door middel van simulaties. Het werkt zo: u neemt enige lichamen, voegt er wat krachten aan toe zoals de zwaartekracht en wat veren, en klikt daarna op de knop Simuleren, waarna Step u laat zien hoe dit stelsel evolueert volgens de natuurkundige wetten. U kunt elke eigenschap van de lichamen en krachten in uw experiment wijzigen (zelfs tijdens de simulatie), en zien wat daarvan de gevolgen zijn. Met Step leert u niet alleen natuurkunde, maar krijgt u er ook gevoel voor!</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Krok jest interaktywnym symulatorem fizyki. Umożliwia poznawanie świata fizycznego poprzez symulacje. Działa w następujący sposób: umieszczasz jakieś bryły na scenie, dodajesz jakieś siły jako grawitacja lub sprężyny, a następnie naciskasz na Symulacja i Krok pokaże jak scena się zmieni według praw fizyki. Można zmienić każdą właściwość brył/sił w eksperymencie (nawet podczas symulacji) i zobaczyć jak zmieni się przebieg eksperymentu. Dzięki Krokowi nie tylko można się nauczyć, ale także poczuć jak działa fizyka!</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Step é um simulador de física interactiva. Permite-lhe explorar o mundo da física através de simulações. Funciona da seguinte forma: poderá colocar alguns corpos na cena, adicionar algumas forças, como a gravidade ou algumas molas, e depois carregar em Simular ou Passo, que lhe mostra como a sua cena irá evoluir de acordo com as leis da física. Poderá mudar todas as propriedades dos corpos/forças da sua experiência (mesmo durante a simulação) e ver como isto irá mudar a evolução da experiência. Com o Passo, poderá não só aprender como também sentir como funciona a física!</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Step é um simulador de física interativo. Permite-lhe explorar o mundo da física através de simulações. Funciona da seguinte forma: Você coloca alguns corpos no cenário, adiciona algumas forças como a gravidade ou molas e então clica em Simular, para que o Step lhe mostre como o seu cenário irá evoluir de acordo com as leis da física. Você poderá alterar qualquer propriedade dos corpos/forças da sua experiência (inclusive durante a simulação) para ver como isso irá mudar a evolução da experiência. Com o Step você poderá não só aprender, mas também sentir como funciona a física!</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Step je interaktívny fyzikálny simulátor. Umožňuje vám objaviť fyzikálny svet cez simulácie. Funguje takto: umiestnite nejaké telesá na scénu, pridáte nejaké sily ako gravitáciu alebo pružiny, potom kliknete na Simulácia a Step vám ukáže, ako sa vaša scéna bude vyvíjať podľa zákonov fyziky. Môžete zmeniť každú vlastnosť telies/síl vo vašom experimente (aj počas simulácie) a vidieť, ako to zmení vývoj experimentu. S programom Step sa nielen učíte, ale aj cítite, ako fyzika funguje!</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Step є інтерактивним імітатором фізичних процесів. Він надає вам змогу вивчати фізичні явища за допомогою їх імітації. Ось як він працює: ви розташовуєте у дослідній області деякі тіла, додаєте сили їх взаємодії (такі як гравітаційні сили та пружні сили у вигляді пружин), а потім натискаєте кнопку «Імітувати», — Step покаже як розвиватимуться події у побудованій вами системі з плином часу згідно до законів фізики. Ви можете змінювати всі властивості тіл або сил у вашому експерименті (навіть під час імітації), щоб побачити як такі зміни впливають на перебіг експерименту. За допомогою Step ви не просто вивчите фізику, а відчуєте як працюють фізичні закони!</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxStep is an interactive physical simulator. It allows you to explore the physical world through simulations. It works like this: you place some bodies on the scene, add some forces such as gravity or springs, then click Simulate and Step shows you how your scene will evolve according to the laws of physics. You can change every property of the bodies/forces in your experiment (even during simulation) and see how this will change evolution of the experiment. With Step you cannot only learn but feel how physics works!xx</p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <p xml:lang="cs">Vlastnosti:</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Funciones:</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Fonctionnalités :</p>
    <p xml:lang="nds">Markmalen:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Mogelijkheden:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Możliwości:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Características:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Funcionalidades:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Funkcie:</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Можливості:</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxFeatures:xx</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Classical mechanical simulation in two dimensions</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Simulación mecánica clásica en dos dimensiones</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Simulation de la mécanique classique en deux dimensions</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Klass'sch mechaansch Simuleren in twee Dimenschonen</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Simulatie in twee dimensies volgens de klassieke mechanica</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Klasyczna symulacja mechaniczna w dwóch wymiarach</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Simulação mecânica clássica a duas dimensões</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Simulação mecânica clássica em duas dimensões</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Simulácie klasickej mechaniky v dvoch rozmeroch</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Імітація класичної механічної взаємодії у двох вимірах</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxClassical mechanical simulation in two dimensionsxx</li>
      <li>Particles, springs with dumping, gravitational and coulomb forces</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Partículas, muelles con amortiguación, fuerzas gravitatorias y de Coulomb</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Particules, ressorts avec amortissement, forces gravitationnelle et coulombienne</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Deeltjes, Feddern mit Dämpen, Swoor- un Coulomb-Kräft</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Deeltjes, veren met demping, zwaarte- en elektrische krachten</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Cząstki, sprężyny z tłumieniem, siły grawitacyjne i kulombowskie</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Partículas, molas com forças potenciais, gravíticas e de Coulomb</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Partículas, molas com forças potenciais, gravitacionais e de Coulomb</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Častice, pružiny s tlakom, gravitačné a coulombove sily</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Частинки, пружини з елементами в’язкості, гравітаційні і кулонові сили</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxParticles, springs with dumping, gravitational and coulomb forcesxx</li>
      <li>Rigid bodies</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Cuerpos rígidos</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Corps rigides</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Fast Körpers</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Stijve lichamen</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Bryły sztywne</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Corpos rígidos</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corpos rígidos</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Tuhé telesá</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Тверді тіла</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxRigid bodiesxx</li>
      <li>Collision detection (currently only discrete) and handling</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Détection et traitement de collisions (actuellement seulement discrète)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Tosamenstoot-Opdecken (opstunns bloots schrittwies) un -Behanneln</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Botsingdetectie (nu nog alleen discreet) en afhandeling</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Wykrywanie i obsługa kolizji (obecnie tylko dyskretnie)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Detecção e tratamento de colisões (somente discretas de momento)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Detecção e tratamento de colisões (atualmente somente discretas)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Detekcia kolízií (aktuálne iba oddelené) a ich spracovanie</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Виявлення (у цій версії лише дискретне) і керування зіткненнями</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxCollision detection (currently only discrete) and handlingxx</li>
      <li>Soft (deformable) bodies simulated as user-editable particles-springs system, sound waves</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Corps mous (déformables) simulés comme un système modifiable par l'utilisateur de particles-ressorts, ondes sonores</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Week (verformbor) Körpers simuleert as för den Bruker bewerkbor Deeltjes-Feddern-Systeem, Klangbülgen</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Zachte (vervormbare) lichamen gesimuleerd als een deeltjes-verensysteem dat door de gebruiker kan worden bewerkt, geluidsgolven</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Miękkie (odkształcalne) bryły symulowane jako systemy cząsteczek-sprężyn edytowanych przez użytkownika, fale dźwiękowe</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Corpos suaves (deformáveis) simulados como um sistema de partículas-ondas editáveis pelo utilizador, ondas sonoras</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Corpos suaves (deformáveis) simulados como um sistema de partículas-ondas editáveis pelo usuário, ondas sonoras</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Mäkké (deformovateľné) telesá simulované ako používateľom upraviteľné systémy častíc-pružín, zvukové vlny</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">М’які (пружні) тіла імітуються як система з часточок і пружин, з можливістю зміни її параметрів користувачем, рух якої описують гармонічні функції</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxSoft (deformable) bodies simulated as user-editable particles-springs system, sound wavesxx</li>
      <li>Molecular dynamics (currently using Lennard-Jones potential): gas and liquid, condensation and evaporation, calculation of macroscopic quantities and their variances</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Dynamique moléculaire (utilisant actuellement un potentiel de Lennard-Jones) : gaz, liquide, condensation et évaporation, calcul de quantités macroscopiques et de leur variance.</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Molekööldünamik  (opstunns mit Lennard-Jones-Potenschaal): Gas un Flaat, kondenseren un verdampen, utreken vun makroskoopsch Mengden un ehr Varianten</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Moleculaire dynamica (thans wordt de Lennard-Jones potentiaal gebruikt): gas en vloeistof, condensatie en verdamping, berekening van macroscopische hoeveelheden met hun variaties</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Dynamika molekularna (obecnie przy użyciu potencjału Lennard-Jones): gaz i ciecz, kondensacja i parowanie, obliczanie wielkości makroskopowych i ich wariancji</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Dinâmica molecular (usando o potencial de Lennard-Jones de momento): gases e líquidos, condensação e evaporação, cálculo de quantidades macroscópicas e as suas variâncias</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Dinâmica molecular (usando o potencial de Lennard-Jones atualmente): gases e líquidos, condensação e evaporação, cálculo de quantidades macroscópicas e as suas variâncias</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Molekulárna dynamika (aktuálne používa Lennardov-Jonesov potenciál): plyn a kvapalina, kondenzácia a vyparovanie, výpočet makroskopických kvantít a ich odchýliek</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Молекулярна динаміка (у цій версії з використанням потенціалу Леннарда-Джонса): газ і рідина, конденсація і випаровування, обчислення макроскопічних величин та їх змін</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxMolecular dynamics (currently using Lennard-Jones potential): gas and liquid, condensation and evaporation, calculation of macroscopic quantities and their variancesxx</li>
      <li>Units conversion and expression calculation: you can enter something like "(2 days + 3 hours) * 80 km/h" and it will be accepted as distance value (requires libqalculate)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Conversion d'unités et calcul d'expression : vous pouvez saisir quelque chose comme "(2 jours + 3 heures) * 80 km/h" et ce sera considéré comme une distance (nécessite libqalculate)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Eenheiten ümreken un Utdrück utreken: Di giffst wat in as „(2 Daag + 3 Stünnen) * 80 km/h“ un dat gellt denn as Längdenweert (bruukt „libqalculate“)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Conversie van eenheden en berekening van expressies zoals "(2 dagen + 3 uren) * 80 km/h", waarna dit zal worden beschouwd als een afstand (vereist libqalculate)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Przekształcanie jednostek i obliczanie wyrażeń: możesz  wpisać coś takiego"(2 dni + 3 godziny) * 80 km/h" i zostanie to potraktowane jako wartość odległości (wymaga libqalculate)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Conversão de unidades e cálculo de expressões; poderá indicar algo do tipo "(2 dias + 3 horas) * 80 km/h", para que seja aceite como um valor de distância (necessita da 'libqalculate')</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Conversão de unidades e cálculo de expressões; você poderá indicar algo do tipo "(2 dias + 3 horas) * 80 km/h", e isto será aceito como um valor de distância (necessita da 'libqalculate')</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Konverzie jednotiek a výpočet výrazov: môžete zadať niečo ako "(2 dni + 3 hodiny) * 80 km/h" a bude to prijaté ako hodnota vzdialenosti (vyžaduje libqalculate)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Перетворення одиниць і обчислення виразів: ви можете ввести щось на зразок «(2 дні + 3 години) * 80 км/г» і цю величину буде прийнято як значення відстані (для того, щоб це працювало слід встановити libqalculate)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxUnits conversion and expression calculation: you can enter something like "(2 days + 3 hours) * 80 km/h" and it will be accepted as distance value (requires libqalculate)xx</li>
      <li>Errors calculation and propagation: you can enter values like "1.3 ± 0.2" for any property and errors for all dependent properties will be calculated using statistical formulas</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Calcul d'erreurs et propagation : you pouvez saisir des valeurs comme "1.3 ± 0.2" pour n'importe quelle propriété et les erreurs pour toutes les propriétés indépendantes seront calculées suivant des formules statistiques</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Fehlerreken: Du kannst wat as „1,3 ± 0,2“ för jichtenseen Egenschap ingeven, denn reekt Step för all afhangen Weerten över statistische Formeln de Fehlers ut.</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Foutenberekening en -voortplanting: u kunt voor elke eigenschap zoiets invullen als "1,3 ± 0,2", waarna voor elke daarvan afhankelijke eigenschap de fouten zullen worden berekend met gebruik van statistische formules</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Obliczanie i propagacja błędów: możesz wpisać wartości takie jak "1.3 ± 0.2" dla każdej własności, a błędy dla wszystkich zależnych własności zostaną obliczone używając równań statystycznych</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Cálculo e propagação de erros: poderá indicar valores do tipo "1.3 ± 0.2" para qualquer propriedade, para que sejam calculados os erros de todas as propriedades dependentes com fórmulas estatísticas</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Cálculo e propagação de erros: você poderá indicar valores do tipo "1.3 ± 0.2" para qualquer propriedade, para que sejam calculados os erros de todas as propriedades dependentes com fórmulas estatísticas</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Výpočet a šírenie chýb: môžete zadať hodnoty ako "1,3 ± 0,2" pre ľubovoľnú vlastnosť a chyby pre všetky závislé vlastnosti sa prepočítajú pomocou štatistických vzorcov</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Обчислення і поширення похибок: ви можете вводити значення на зразок «1.3 ± 0.2» для будь-якої з властивостей, і похибки для всіх властивостей, що залежать від вказаної властивості, буде обчислено за статистичними формулами</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxErrors calculation and propagation: you can enter values like "1.3 ± 0.2" for any property and errors for all dependent properties will be calculated using statistical formulasxx</li>
      <li>Solver error estimation: errors introduced by the solver is calculated and added to user-entered errors</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Estimation des erreurs du solveur : les erreurs introduites par le solveur sont calculées et ajoutées aux erreurs saisies par l'utilisateur</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Löserfehler-Estemeren: Vun den Löser inbuut Fehlers warrt estemeert un de vun den Bruker ingeven Fehlers toföögt</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Het afschatten van fouten veroorzaakt door de oplossingsmethode: fouten die bij het oplossen zijn ontstaan worden berekend en opgeteld bij de fouten die door de gebruiker zijn ingevoerd</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Oszacowanie błędu solvera: błędy wprowadzone przez solver są obliczane i dodawane do błędów podanych przez użytkownika</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Estimativa do erro da resolução: os erros introduzidos pela resolução são calculados e adicionados aos erros introduzidos pelo utilizador</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Estimativa do erro da resolução: os erros introduzidos pela resolução são calculados e adicionados aos erros adicionados pelo usuário</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Odhad chýb riešiteľa: chyby spôsobené riešiteľom sa počítajú a pridávajú do používateľom zadaných chýb</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Оцінка похибки розв’язувача: похибки, що виникають внаслідок застосування числових методів розв’язання задач, обчислюються і додаються до введених користувачем похибок</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxSolver error estimation: errors introduced by the solver is calculated and added to user-entered errorsxx</li>
      <li>Several different solvers: up to 8th order, explicit and implicit, with or without adaptive timestep (most of the solvers require GSL library)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Plusieurs solveurs différents :jusqu'à l'ordre 8, explicite et implicite, avec ou sans pas adaptatif (la plupart des solveurs nécessite la bibliothèque GSL)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">En Reeg verscheden Lösers: bet to de 8. Orden, ex- un implizit, mit un ahn topassen Tietschreed (de mehrsten Lösers bruukt de GSL-Bibliotheek)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Er zijn diverse oplossingsmethoden: tot aan de 8e orde, expliciet en impliciet, met of zonder een adaptieve tijdstap (voor de meesten is de GSL-bibliotheek nodig)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Kilka różnych solwerów: aż do 8-mego rzędu, uwikłane i nieuwikłane, z lub bez adaptowanego kroku czasowego (większość z solwerów wymaga biblioteki GSL)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Diversos métodos de resolução diferentes: até à 8a ordem, explícitos e implícitos, com ou sem passos temporais adaptativos (a maioria destes métodos necessitam da biblioteca GSL)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Diversos métodos de resolução diferentes: até à 8ª ordem, explícitos e implícitos, com ou sem passos temporais adaptativos (a maioria destes métodos necessitam da biblioteca GSL)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Niekoľko rôznych riešiteľov: do 8. úrovne, explicitné a implicitné, s alebo bez adaptívnej časovej pečiatky (väčšina riešiteľov vyžaduje knižnicu GSL)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Декілька різних розв’язувачів: аж до восьмого порядку, явні і неявні, з та без зміни кроку за часом (більшість з розв’язувачів потребують бібліотеки GSL)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxSeveral different solvers: up to 8th order, explicit and implicit, with or without adaptive timestep (most of the solvers require GSL library)xx</li>
      <li>Controller tool to easily control properties during simulation (even with custom keyboard shortcuts)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Un régulateur pour contrôler facilement les propriétés pendant la simulation (même avec des raccourcis claviers prédéfinis)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Kuntrullwarktüüch för't Bekieken vun Egenschappen binnen de Simuleren (ok mit topasst Tastkombinatschoon)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Hulpmiddel voor het eenvoudig beheersen van eigenschappen tijdens een simulatie (zelfs met aangepaste sneltoetsen)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Narzędzie sterujące do łatwego sterowania właściwościami podczas symulacji (nawet przy użyciu własnych skrótów klawiszowych)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Uma ferramenta de controlo para modificar facilmente as propriedades durante a simulação (até mesmo com atalhos de teclado personalizados)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Uma ferramenta de controle para modificar facilmente as propriedades durante a simulação (até mesmo com atalhos de teclado personalizados)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Nástroj ovládača na jednoduché ovládanie vlastností počas simulácie (dokonca s vlastnými klávesovými skratkami)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Інструмент «регулятор» призначено для простого керування властивостями під час імітації (можна навіть призначити власні клавіатурні скорочення для керування регулятором)</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxController tool to easily control properties during simulation (even with custom keyboard shortcuts)xx</li>
      <li>Tools to visualize results: graph, meter, tracer</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Outils pour visualiser les résultats : graphe, capteur, traceur</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Warktüüch, mit de sik de Resultaten ankieken laat: Diagramm, Meter, Spoor</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Hulpmiddelen voor het visualiseren van de resultaten: grafiek, meter, spoor</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Narzędzia do wizualizacji wyników: wykres, miara, wskaźnik</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Ferramentas para visualização dos resultados: gráficos, medidores, impressão</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Ferramentas para visualização dos resultados: gráficos, medidores, impressão</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Nástroje na vizualizáciu výsledkov: graf, meter, stopár</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Інструменти для візуалізації результатів: графік, вимірювач, траєкторія</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxTools to visualize results: graph, meter, tracerxx</li>
      <li>Context information for all objects, integrated wikipedia browser</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Informations contextuelles pour tous les objets, accès à Wikipédia</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Kontextinformatschonen för all Objekten, inbuut Wikipedia-Kieker</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Contextinformatie voor alle objecten, geïntegreerde wikipedia-browser</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Kontekstowe informacje dla wszystkich obiektów, zintegrowana przeglądarka wikipedi</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Informação de contexto para todos os objectos, navegador do Wikipédia integrado</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Informação de contexto para todos os objetos, navegador do Wikipédia integrado</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Kontextové informácie pre všetky objekty, integrovaný prehliadač Wikipédia</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Контекстна інформація щодо всіх об’єктів, інтегрований переглядач вікіпедії</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxContext information for all objects, integrated wikipedia browserxx</li>
      <li>Collection of example experiments, more can be downloaded with KNewStuff</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Collection d'exemples d'expérience, davantage peuvent être téléchargé avec KNewStuff</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Sammeln vun Bispill-Experimenten, mehr laat sik vun KNewStuff daalladen</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Verzameling van voorbeeldexperimenten, meer kunnen er worden opgehaald met KNewStuff</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Zbiór przykładowych eksperymentów, można pobrać więcej z KNewStuff</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Uma colecção de experiências de exemplo, podendo obter mais com o KNewStuff</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Coleção de experiências de exemplo, podendo obter mais com o KNewStuff</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Kolekcia ukážkových experimentov, viac je možné stiahnuť z KNewStuff</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Збірка зразкових експериментів, додаткові експерименти можна звантажити за допомогою KNewStuff</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxCollection of example experiments, more can be downloaded with KNewStuffxx</li>
      <li>Integrated tutorials</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Tutoriels intégrés</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Inbuut Anleden</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Geïntegreerd lesmateriaal</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Zintegrowane samouczki</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Tutoriais integrados</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Tutoriais integrados</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Integrované kurzy</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Вбудовані підручники</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxIntegrated tutorialsxx</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://edu.kde.org/step/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=step</url>
  <url type="help">http://docs.kde.org/stable/en/kdeedu/step/index.html</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>http://kde.org/images/screenshots/step.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>step</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
